UMMUGULSUM ARSLAN

CONTACT

Address: San Antonio TX 78251

Phone: 210-712-0024

Email: ummuglsmarsIn@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Programming:
- · Python,
- R,
- · SQL,
- SAS
 - ❖ Tools:
- Spark,
- · Hadoop,
- · Pandas,
- · Scikit Learn,
- · Seaborn,
- PostgreSQL,
- Plotly,
- Tableau,

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Strong background and experience in Data Science, machine learning, probability and statistics theory. • Well versed with Linear/non-linear, regression and classification modeling predictive algorithms in machine learning. • Experienced in writing complex SQL queries in performing Data analysis. • Guiding analytical team members in implementation and execution of machine learning models at different levels of project life cycle. • Experienced in working with both technical and non-technical team members. • Experience with regression and classification models such as Random Forest, KNN, K-Means. Dependable Graduate Assistant accustomed to assisting professors with Statistics and R-Python to drive Data Science.

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Applied Statistic And Data Science, Expected in 05/2022

The University of Texas At San Antonio - San Antonio, TX

Data Science Certification: Data Science And ML Bootcamp, 08/2020 **Al Data Science Academy** - California

AI / Data Science Academy, Data Science Certification

- Principles of Data Science
- Supervised and Unsupervised Learning
- Statistical Analysis of Machine Learning models
- Bayesian Methods to Machine Learning
- Deep Learning with Tensorflow and Keras
- Handwritten digit detection using mixture of supervised and unsupervised methods
- Sentiment Analysis using NLP bag-of-words methods
- Dimensionality reduction for optimizing Machine Learning model performance
- Transfer Learning
- Reinforcement Learning
- Arima Time-series Analysis
- Dynamic Programming
- · Analysis of time and space complexity of algorithms
- Visualization of model features and model performance
- Deploying Machine Learning models to production

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics Education, 08/2015 **Erciyes University** - Kayseri, Turkey

WORK HISTORY

Graduate Teaching Assistant, 07/2020 to Current **University of Texas at San Antonio** - San Antonio, TX

 Taught Python, Statistic, Applied statistic, Data Science for more than 300 stat and Data Science students Collaborated with professors to implement lecture and testing materials, graded R labs. Troubleshoot students R labs and projects. Researched Data Science to assist with academic projects.

High School Mathematics Teacher/Coach, 10/2018 to Current **Premier High School, SST** - San Antonio, TX

Taught all levels of mathematics from middle school to college level including Pre Calculus , Statistics.

- Used Genius, Schoology etc. to teach and meet with students and absence data into district computer systems.
- Increased passing rate for over %50

Python Programming Instructor, 08/2019 to 07/2020 **School of Science and Technology** - San Antonio, TX

• .Coached, established Python Projects with Advanced Math students. 80% of students completed their projects.

PROJECTS

- *Data Science Real Life Project> Vehicle Location Simulation
- Answered:
- Where was the vehicle after exactly M steps?
- How many u-turns were made in the first M steps?
- How many times did we avoid going farther?
- How far was the farthest point reached by the vehicle?
- How many times did the simulation end by reaching the starting point (without setting to True)
- ...etc... by using Statistical Distributions and Data Visualization tools to show 3D or plots.
- *R Shiny Application- I created Iris r shiny app Advance R programming class finish project
- *Web Scraping and Data Visualization> I scrapped the data by using R programming for CDC website to make prediction for C-19 data accuracy and the potential hazard.
- *Census Data Analysis on SAS > I download the data from Census.gov and import it to SAS and I used the statistical data (correlation etc.) to see the median home value and how it changed during the time and how it differs from states to state in US (I got the US Census)